Alexander Larsen

5443 Serviceberry, Centreville VA, 20120

PHONE (920) 246-8971 E-MAIL Alarsen525@gmail.com

LINKEDIN www.linkedin.com/in/a-w-larsen

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Multi-purpose Language

- Python
- R
- C++
- JavaScript
- Bash scripting

Sublanguages

- SQL
- MongoDB
- CSS/HTML

System / Support

- Git
- AWS CLI
- REST API
- Docker
- GIMP img editor

SUMMARY

Statistical analyst of Next Generation Sequencing (NGS) data as it relates to clinical applications. Excels in both fast-paced environments with urgent clinical results and methodical high dimensional data analysis. Automates multi-language bioinformatic software and tool development with an emphasis on python. Works with business partners and other researchers coordinating projects and public speaking. A self-directed learner, highly collaborative, and excellent at working autonomously.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Designed automated COVID-19 report end to end software.
- Developed metagenomic analysis library that automatically pulls, graphs, and models metadata.
- Designed automated multi-process Human Microbiome Project Whole Genome Sequencing (WGS) metagenomic pipeline.
- Created rapid primer design tools for over 10,000 different microscopic species.
- Presented on bioinformatics clinical value to congress representative and at other local events.
- Published scientific article with first authorship.

EXPERIENCE

Clinical Bioinformatician II

Aperiomics Inc.

June 2018 - Current

Sterling, VA

- Pipeline software development and module creation. Python, SQL, command-line/bash, C++, HTML, CSS, Javascript and R • Quality control and standards development.
- NGS protocols optimization and data analysis. Statistical modeling, Bayesian, Regression, PCoA, diversity. analysis.
- Public speaking, clinician consults, and patient customer service.
- Publication writing, SOP writing, and publication grade image editing.

Undergraduate Researcher

University of Wisconsin Madison

Apr 2013 - May 2016

Madison, WI

- Characterizing circadian rhythm genes and their temporal effect on long term memory formation in drosophila.
 Particular effort towards the quality control of data and samples.
- Characterizing zebrafish embryonic development, crayfish nerve reading frequencies, and rat hippocampal electrical activity.

EDUCATION / CERTIFICATIONS

Bioinformatics Micromasters Certificate

UMGC - edX

Mar 2019 – Jan 2020

Adelphi, MD

Proteins and DNA: Alignment, Statistical Analysis, and Structure. BIF001x - BIF003x

Bioinformatics Audited – UW Madison / MIT Open Courseware

June 2017 - Apr 2018

De Pere, WI

• Graduate studies following UW Madison outlines for a master's in bioinformatics.

• Statistics, bioinformatic algorithms I/II, general algorithms / data structures, artificial intelligence.

B.S. Neurobiology

University of Wisconsin Madison

Sept 2012 - May 2016

Madison, WI

• Graduated from a selective honors biology program which facilitated group directed research, scientific writing, and analysis. — UW Madison Biocore program.